(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
不知火フレア 3D新ビジュアルお披露目
Shiranui Flare 3D New Visual Reveal
君に...
作詞/作曲 川嶋あい
To You...
Lyrics/Composition: Ai Kawashima
君に...
To you...
君に出会えなかったら
If I hadn't met you
僕は何をしていたのかわからない
I don't know what I would have been doing
どうしてなんだろう 今日はなぜか
I wonder why... for some reason, today
たまらないほど泣きたくなるんだ
I feel like crying so much I can't bear it
夕暮れの風に吹かれ
Blown by the evening breeze
二人でずっと話したあの夏に
In that summer when we talked forever
心から僕はただ
From the bottom of my heart, I just
本当の恋をしたんだね
fell in true love, didn't I?
君を守る強さが
If the strength to protect you
もっとあれば僕は君を幸せにできるのかな
was greater, I wonder if I could make you happy
愛することと信じることの意味が今
Now that the meaning of loving and believing
分かったら二人で乗り越えられる
is clear, we can overcome it together
君がいてくれて 本当に良かった
I'm so glad that you are here
この手を繋いで握って 満たされてゆく
Holding and squeezing this hand, I am being filled
二人の指先は 明日を指さす
Our fingertips point towards tomorrow
溢れる気持ちが 未来にほら
Look, these overflowing feelings
向かっていくよ
are heading towards the future
君が教えてくれたね
You taught me, didn't you?
ちっぽけでささやかな幸せたち
Those tiny and modest moments of happiness
いつの間にか君のこと
Before I knew it, you...
誰よりも愛していたんだ
I was loving you more than anyone else
隣でいつも君がいて笑ってる
You are always there beside me, laughing
それだけで僕はただ幸せなんだ
Just with that, I am simply happy
切なさに似たもどかしさを抱えていた
I was holding onto a frustration similar to sadness
逃げないで真っ直ぐ届けてみるよ
I won't run away, I'll try to deliver it straight
時に壊れそうで震える想いが
Sometimes, feelings so fragile they might break
君を傷つけてしまうよ どうしようもない
will end up hurting you, and I can't help it
追い越せないよ
I can't overtake them
流れてゆく雲
The drifting clouds
大好きの気持ち
The feeling of 'I love you'
一つまた増えていたよ
one more has grown again
…好き
...I love you.
二人乗りで出かけた自転車
On the bicycle we rode together,
降りも厭い いつもそばに君が
Not minding the rain, you were always...
いてくれたんだ
...there by my side.
思い出の数だけ重なる思い
Feelings overlapping as many as our memories,
遠回りもしてやっと辿り着いた
Taking a detour, I finally arrived.
君といる世界は 運命の奇跡
The world with you is a miracle of fate.
過去も今も未来も全部 輝きだすよ
The past, present, and future all begin to shine.
君がいてくれて 本当によかった
I'm so glad you're here.
伝えたいことが溢れて 止まらないよ
The things I want to tell you are overflowing.
永遠の先のゴールに 君がきっときっと
At the goal beyond eternity, I hope you'll...
いてくれればいい
...surely, surely be there.
本当にありがとう
Thank you so much.
はいみんな、こんぬい！
Hi everyone, Kon-nui!
今の雰囲気ぶち壊しやな（笑）
I totally ruined the atmosphere just now, didn't I? (laughs)
はいということで、皆さん、新ビジュアル3D来ました！
So, everyone, the new 3D visual is here!
みんな本当にお待たせいたしました。
Thank you all for waiting.
見て見て、どう？可愛いでしょ？
Look, look, how is it? Isn't it cute?
見て見て、いっぱいあの、下からとかも撮ってもらったんだけど
Look, look! I had them take lots of shots, like from below and stuff.
ちょっとじっくり見てほしいなって思ったり、でも時間もそんなにないので
I want you to take a good look, but we don't have that much time.
あの、後でね、ちょっとあのある人たちをゲストに呼びましたので
Later, I've invited some certain people as guests.
そこでもね、撮影会をしたいなと思っております！
So I'm thinking of having a photo session there too!
っていうか季節ガン無視ってな！
I mean, I'm totally ignoring the season, aren't I!
ま、でもね、バーチャル地方なんで。バーチャル地方はちょっと早めの春が来ております
Well, but it's the virtual region. Spring has come a bit early in the virtual region.
4月誕生日なんでね、まちょっと春なんだと思います
Since my birthday is in April, well, I guess it's spring.
なんてな！や、今回はですね、あのカッコいい曲も結構用意させていただいています
Just kidding! Well, this time, I've prepared quite a few cool songs.
みんなが好きな曲とか、なんか盛り上がる曲とか、楽しい曲とか
Songs you all like, songs that'll get us hyped, fun songs, and more.
たくさん用意させていただいておりますので、みんなも一緒に盛り上がってくれたら嬉しいです
I've prepared a lot, so I'd be happy if everyone gets hyped with me.
まちょっとね、私、あの喋るのがめっちゃ歌枠とかの時もそうなんですけど
Well, I'm... talking is something I'm really bad at, like during karaoke streams.
歌後だとすごい喋り下手になってしまうので、まちょっとトーク短めかもしれませんが
After singing, I get really bad at talking, so the talk sections might be a bit short.
この後もいっぱい楽しんでいただけたらなと思います
But I hope you continue to enjoy yourself after this.
余すところなくね、あの写真撮ってほしいです。
Please take lots of pictures without missing a single thing.
あのハッシュタグどっちに出るかな？こっちかな？
Which side will the hashtag appear on? This side?
じゃこっちに、あのハッシュタグ是非あのここに乗ってるやつをいっぱいツイートしてスクショ撮ってくれたら嬉しいです
Then on this side, please tweet using the hashtag shown here and take lots of screenshots, I'd be happy.
よろしくお願いします！
Please!
いっぱい撮ってね！
Take lots of them!
色んな歌で、あの歌うのでポーズもいっぱいとるのでいっぱい写真撮ってください。お願いします
I'll be singing various songs and striking lots of poses, so please take lots of photos. Please.
じゃちょっと次の曲もね、この桜並木せっかくなのでここで歌おうかなって思っています
Well then, for the next song, since we're here at this cherry blossom-lined path, I think I'll sing it here.
是非是非皆さん最後まで聴いてくださいね！
Please, everyone, listen until the very end!
ということでよろしくお願いします！えーとでは…
So, here we go! Um, then...
最後の曲…最後の曲じゃないわ まだ始まったばかりや。
The last song... It's not the last song, it's just started.
次の曲に行きたいと思います
I'd like to go to the next song.
ダヴィンチの告白
Da Vinci's Confession
どんなに有名でも伝えきれない
No matter how famous, I can't fully convey it.
こんなに高評価が描いてんのに分かんねーのか
Even though it's drawn with such high evaluation, don't you get it?
盤石の宗教裁判
The solid religious trial.
骨ないエミネンティー円満な解決法はこれからさ
Eminence with no trick, the harmonious solution starts now.
散々な目に遭いました 自主マニアリズムに肖って
I went through a terrible time, following voluntary mannerism.
全部が僕の罪と罰です 嘘偽りの愛を愛想
It's all my crime and punishment, love the false love.
簡単な役演じきって 困難な道歩んだって
Playing a simple role, even if I walked a difficult path.
記憶のない白黒映画は耐えられないさ
I can't stand a black and white movie with no memory.
存在革命 剥がれて
The existential revolution is peeling off,
風景を再生活認
Reconfirming the scenery.
IQ make you just alike you
この世界の片隅 丸くなっていた
In a corner of this world, it was curled up.
ありふれた顔にいい…
On a common face...
...ってさせて
...let me do that
このままだれにも会わないでいて
Please don't meet anyone else like this
ベンチのままに今
Remaining as a bench now
It's ordinary love
乱数調整なんて当てにならない
Random number adjustments are unreliable
信じられるのは自分だからそりゃそうだろ
I can only believe in myself, so that makes sense
情弱な先入観で三つの地球を
With weak-information preconceptions, three Earths...
凡庸という箱に押し込めて
...are pushed into a box called "mediocre"
恋したって冷めたら愛なんて忘れるさ
Even if you're in love, if you cool down, you'll forget about love
灰になって後悔したって風に乗って流されて
Even if you regret turning to ash, you're carried away by the wind
ハイになって脂肪記事を眺める優越感を
Getting high and looking at fat articles, a sense of superiority...
愛になって教科書に乗ってなんて夢見るの
...dreaming of becoming love and appearing in textbooks
宣戦布告的正攻法で
With a declaration of war-like frontal assault
融解を創生 法崩壊
Creating fusion, law collapse
I'll make you just like you
ラララ...
La la la...
この世界の片隅誰かが泣いていた
In a corner of this world, someone was crying
無力な自分を見ているようだ
It's like looking at my powerless self
この先60年を有意義に生きて
Live the next 60 years meaningfully
ベンチのままに今 It's ordinary love
Remaining as a bench now, it's ordinary love
こんぬい！準備はいいかー？
Kon-nui! Are you ready?
今日はみんなで騒ぎましょー！せーの！
Let's make some noise together today! One, two!
Smile and Go!!!
作詞/作曲：桃充花、福嶋あやと
Lyrics/Composition: Momomitsuka, Ayato Fukushima
やってきましたみんなに会える時間で
The time has come to meet everyone
歌とかゲームとか見て欲しくて
I want you to see my singing and games
配信、見てください！
Please watch the stream!
あっという間に過ぎてしまう毎日に
In the days that pass by in the blink of an eye
乗り遅れないように手繋ごう
Let's hold hands so we don't get left behind
もっともっと一緒にいよう
Let's stay together more and more
気づけば隣にいてくれてありがとう
Thank you for being by my side before I knew it
どんな高い壁だってひとっ飛びで飛び越えて
No matter how high the wall, jump over it in one leap
誰も見たことない世界にみんなで行こうよ
Let's all go to a world no one has seen before
君とSmile and Go 楽しんだもん勝ち
With you, Smile and Go, the one who enjoys it wins
君とSmile and Go 弾けたもん勝ち
With you, Smile and Go, the one who pops wins
ここに笑顔で集まれば最高でしょ
It's the best if we gather here with smiles, right?
僕らSmile and Go 今全速力で
We, Smile and Go, now at full speed
僕らSmile and Go 遊びまくろうぜ
We, Smile and Go, let's play to our heart's content
だってこの日常が大切な宝物だよ
Because this everyday life is a precious treasure
Smile and Go!!!
雑談配信今日はまったり行きましょう
Today's chat stream, let's take it easy
他愛ない話聞いてほしくて
I want you to hear some trivial talk
見て見て、ちょっと聞いてよ！
Look, look, listen for a bit!
たまにはお休みしようと思ったけれど
I thought about taking a break once in a while, but...
やっぱりわちゃわちゃ配信しちゃおっかな
I guess I'll do a noisy stream after all
用意はできた？
Are you ready?
ありふれたこの時も一緒に過ごしたら
If we spend even this commonplace time together
いつのまにかキラキラと何よりも輝いて
Before I knew it, it shone more than anything
言葉にはできない想いがあふれ出しちゃうよ
Feelings that can't be put into words are overflowing
君とLet's Enjoy 歌ってみようよ
With you, Let's Enjoy, let's try singing
君とLet's Enjoy 心は一つに
With you, Let's Enjoy, hearts as one
そこにいたって優しさは届いてるよ
Even if you're there, the kindness is reaching me
僕らLet's Enjoy テンション上げてさ
We, Let's Enjoy, let's raise the tension
僕らLet's Enjoy はしゃぎまくろうぜ
We, Let's Enjoy, let's frolic around
きっと明日はもっと楽しいこと待っているから
Because surely even more fun things are waiting tomorrow
みんなー！お披露目盛り上がってますかー！？
Everyone! Are you getting excited for the reveal!?
可愛くなった私を余すところなく...
Don't miss a single bit of the cuter me...
3, 2, 1, Go!
ずっと見ていて 私のことを
Keep watching me
これから先も 期待してね
And keep expecting great things from now on
予測不可能なワクワクを
Unpredictable excitement
君に送るから
I'll send it to you
君とSmile and Go! 楽しんだもん勝ち
With you, Smile and Go! The one who enjoys it wins
君とSmile and Go! 弾けたもん勝ち
With you, Smile and Go! The one who pops off wins
ここに笑顔で集まれば
If we gather here with smiles
最高でしょう
It'll be the best, right?
覚悟とSmile and Go! もお全力で
With determination and Smile and Go! At full power
覚悟とSmile and Go! 遊びまくなわだって
With determination and Smile and Go! Let's play all out
この日常が大切な宝物だよ
This everyday life is a precious treasure
とびきりの笑顔で行こう
Let's go with our best smiles
Smile and Go!
はい！やあないと思いましたがSmile and Go!
Yes! You probably thought it wouldn't happen, but Smile and Go!
実は中に入れてみました！
Actually, I put it right in the middle!
最初に来ないってことはあとは最後かなーとかね、
Since it didn't come first, I'm sure some people thought...
考えた人もいるんじゃないですか？
...maybe it would be last?
まさかこんなところで来るなんて思ってもいなかっただろう！
You probably didn't expect it to come at a time like this!
ちょ、ちょっと待ってめっちゃ疲れたｗ
Wait, wait a second. I'm exhausted! lol
いやーなんかね、今日はね、あのー気持ち程度のね、エルフェンドちょっとね、添えさせていただいたんですけど
Well, today, I've added a little bit of Elfriends to the mix.
これね、EN日記も見てるー？
Are you watching, EN Nikki?
Lookie! Lookie Elfriend, thank you! Thank you for watching!
そして、JP日記も見ているかー！
And are you watching, JP Nikki?!
まあこれでねきっとね気持ちは通じてると思うんで、
Well, I'm sure my feelings are getting through now.
全く今動きませんけど、
I'm not moving at all right now, but...
みんなの心の中はねもう躍動している、
...I'm sure everyone's hearts are racing.
あまりの感動にフレアちゃんが僕を見てくれたときっと思っている、よな？
You're all probably thinking, "Flare-chan looked at me!" right?
まあそんな感じでですね、まあちょっと中間にオリ曲を入れさせていただきました！
So, like that, I've put an original song in the middle!
この後はですね、まあちょっとかっこいい系の曲、もしくは、綺麗かな？
After this, well, maybe some cool songs, or maybe something beautiful?
なんかみんなが結構好きな曲とか、私が好きな曲を入れさせていただきましたので、
I've included songs that everyone likes and songs that I like...
そちらもね、あのー聴いていただきたいなって思うんですけど
...so I'd like you to listen to those too.
もう一回ねあのステージを変えさせていただこうかなと思います
I think I'll change the stage once more.
なんでアリーナを挟んだのかというと、やっぱなんかこう、
The reason I put the arena in between is, you know...
この曲はね、みんなとここで盛り上がりたいなと思いましたので、
...I wanted to get hyped up with everyone here for this song.
一旦こちらに飛ばさせていただきました！
So I jumped over here for a bit!
ということでですね、えー引き続き、
So, following that,
まだまだいろいろ歌っていきますので、
I'm going to keep singing more songs,
盛り上がっていってくれると嬉しいです！
and I hope you'll keep getting hyped up!
では！まだまだ続いて楽しんでくれると嬉しいです！
Well then! I hope you continue to enjoy what's coming next!
この世で造花より綺麗な花はないわ
In this world, there is no flower more beautiful than an artificial one
なぜならば全ては嘘で出来てる アンチパシー
Because everything is made of lies, antipathy
絶望の雨は私の傘を突いて
The rain of despair pokes at my umbrella
湿らす前髪と心の何れ 煩わしいわ
My bangs and heart are both getting wet; it's annoying
いつしか言の葉はとうに枯れきって
Before I knew it, my words had long since withered away
言のみがたしに熟れている
Only the "fruit of words" is ripening
鏡に映り嘘描いて 自らを見失った
Reflecting in the mirror, painting lies, I've lost sight of myself
ルラパッパッパラ ナゾナゾ数えて遊びましょう
Rura-pappa-para, let's play by counting riddles
ルラパッパッパラ なぜなぜここで踊ってるのでしょう
Rura-pappa-para, why, oh why, am I dancing here?
簡単なことも解らないわ あたしって何だっけ
I don't even understand simple things; what was "I" again?
それすら夜の手 解されて 愛の様に
Even that is unraveled by the hand of night, like love
さよならも言えぬまま泣いた フォニィ 嘘に絡まって
I cried without being able to say goodbye, Phony, entangled in lies
…私はフォニイ
...I am a phony.
いつしか空の願いが嫌になって
Before I knew it, I grew tired of the sky's wishes,
色の眼があなたを解いている
and eyes of color are unraveling you.
鏡に映る私を欠いて
Lacking the me reflected in the mirror,
誰もが見間違ってフェイク
everyone mistakes me for a fake.
どうして愛なんてものに群がり
Why do we flock to things like love,
それを欲して生きるのだ 今日も
and live our lives wanting it even today?
泳いでいる夜の電車が通り去っていく
The night train I'm swimming in passes by.
踊り明かせよ
Dance the night away.
パッパッパラッパッパラッパッパ
(Pappapparappapparappappa)
なになに 騙し打っていきましょう
What, what? Let's go with a sneak attack.
パッパッパラッパッパラッパッパ
(Pappapparappapparappappa)
なぜなぜ ここが痛むのでしょうか
Why, why? Does it hurt here?
散々な日々は変わらないわ
These terrible days won't change.
絶望の雨は止まないわ
The rain of despair won't stop.
さよならも言えぬまま泣いた
I cried without even being able to say goodbye.
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
Phony, phony, phony.
嘘に絡まっている ただ
Just entangled in lies.
簡単なことも解らないわ
I don't even understand simple things.
あたしって何だっけ
Who was I again?
それすら夜の手にほだされて アイノヨニ
Even that is tamed by the night's hand, like love.
さよならまたねと呟いた
I muttered "Goodbye, see you again."
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
Phony, phony, phony.
嘘に絡まっているあたしはフォニイ
Entangled in lies, I am a phony.
風だけが知っている秘密のフォニイ
A secret phony that only the wind knows.
ファティマ
作詞 / 作曲：志倉 千代丸
Fatima
Lyrics / Composition: Chiyomaru Shikura
この世界は非現実 ただ すり込まれたビジョン
This world is unreal, just an imprinted vision.
無限遠点 価値観を今 上書きする
Overwriting values now at the point of infinity.
変哲のない宇宙
An ordinary universe.
傲慢な神は目に映らない
An arrogant god is invisible to the eye,
光速度で支配し続ける ならば
continuing to dominate at the speed of light; then,
僕は
I,
僕だけは
I alone...
奇跡的で致命的なマイノリティでいい
It's fine to be a miraculous and fatal minority.
I can fly high
あの瞬間 あの場面が 君にとって特別なら
If that moment, that scene, is special to you,
過去は離れゆくものなんかじゃなくて
the past isn't something that just drifts away.
一つ付くことの痛みより 大事な真相の全ての
Rather than the pain of a single prick, all of the important truth...
光がいまゼロを生む
The light now gives birth to zero.
There is no God, Wonderful New World
この命という有限 まだ 咲くと知らず
This finite thing called life, not yet knowing it will bloom.
二律背反 パラドックスさえ
Antinomy, even a paradox,
限りない世界線であざむき
deceiving in an endless world line.
感情の支配
Control of emotions,
軌道秩序は
orbital order,
常識さえすり替えてゆく ならば
even common sense is being replaced; then,
僕の
my,
僕だけの
my own...
苦しみその欠陥さえ アルゴリズムのまま
Suffering, even those flaws, remain as part of the algorithm.
I can fly high
愛の標 愛の言葉 明確になるこの記憶を
Signs of love, words of love, this memory that becomes clear...
二度と彼方に置き去りにはしないから
I will never leave it behind in the distance again.
いつでもまだ君のそばに
I'm still always by your side.
隣り合わせの量子が
When adjacent quanta
もつれ合えばゼロになる
entangle, they become zero.
There is no God, Wonderful New World
The phrase is once, or visit twice...
まだ知らない　新し空
A new sky I still don't know
世界線へ繋ぐのさ
It connects to a world line
I can fly high あの瞬間 あの場面が
君にとって特別なら
I can fly high, if that moment, that scene
Is special to you
過去は離れていくものなんかじゃなくて
The past is not something that just drifts away
傷つくことの痛みより大事な真相の全ての
More important than the pain of being hurt,
all the truth's...
光が今ゼロを生む
Light now gives birth to zero
Change the flow.
Wonderful new world.
あー、楽しかったなー！
Ah, that was fun!
え、なんかここも結構見たことあるな。
Somehow, I've seen this place quite a bit too.
なんか遊園地感ある。すごい、中、桃がすごいもんね。
It feels like a theme park. Wow, the peaches
inside are amazing.
ちょっとお借りしてきました！
I've borrowed it for a bit!
ま、ここでもちょっとゲストをここで
呼ばせていただいて、
Well, I'd like to invite some guests here too,
ちょっとみんなと盛り上がりたいなーなんて
思っているわけなんですよねー。
and have some fun with everyone, you see.
え、ちょっと一人ずつ呼んでいこうかなと
思うんですけど、いいですか？
I'm thinking of calling them out one by one,
is that okay?
じゃあまずね、ポルちゃん！
First off, Pol-chan!
どっちだ？ こっちだ！ ポルちゃーん！
Which way? This way! Pol-chaaan!
わぁー！ ポルちゃん！
Waa! Pol-chan!
ありがとう来てくれて！ はい、ありがとう！
Thanks for coming! Yes, thanks!
いやー、照れますな。
Man, I'm blushing.
いやー、どうもありがとうございます。
Well, thank you very much.
お忙しい中していただいて本当にこの度ありがー
Thank you so much for taking the time out of
your busy schedule-
あ、こちら名刺ですね。
Ah, here's my business card.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
あ、こちら副社長の尾丸ポルカでございます。
Ah, I am Vice President Omaru Polka.
身内かい！
You're one of us!
はい、ということでね、どうもありがとう！
Alright then, thanks a lot!
じゃあね！
See ya!
じゃあ次、みこち！
Next, Miko-chi!
次が...
Next is...
ポルカさん触らないでよ、まだ外なんだから！
Polka-san, don't touch me! We're still outside!
みこちー！
Miko-chi!
ちょっと楽しいんですがー！
This is kind of fun!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
人事人事。あたいが出世したの。
HR, HR. I've been promoted.
人事人事。人事部長？
HR, HR. HR Manager?
違う、教育部長なの！
No, I'm the Education Manager!
教育部長なの。教育部長なんですけどみこーん。
The Education Manager. Education Manager, but Miko-n...
教育ね。教育部長に出世したさくらみこさんです。
Education, huh. It's Sakura Miko-san,
who was promoted to Education Manager.
はい！ 部長です！
Yes! Manager here!
どうもしらぬいの部長ですがもー。
Hello, I'm Shiranui's manager.
ちょっと人事がヤバい。
The personnel is a bit crazy.
ちょっと新しくね入ってくる子がみんなどんどん
ヤバい子が多いということで心配です今後ね。
I'm worried about the future because more and
more crazy kids are joining us.
ヤバくないですよね。
We're not crazy, right?
教育できているんでしょうか。
Is the education working, I wonder?
ま、ちょっと不安なんですけどねー。
I'm a bit anxious, though.
今、教育中の星街！
Currently under education, Hoshimachi!
教育できてないですよ！ まったく！
The education isn't working! Not at all!
ヤバいよ！
This is bad!
ヤバいですよ。どんな教育してんだ。
It's bad. What kind of education is this?
もうなんかベッドをたくさん置く教育しか
さーさーせてもらーさせられてないです。
The only education I'm getting is... being
told to place lots of beds.
待って待って！ 星街のために並べてんだから、ベッド！
Wait, wait! I'm lining up beds for
Suisei's sake!
そっか。村人たちの為じゃないんだ。
I see. So it's not for the villagers.
村人増やしてー
Increase the villagers-
そう。村人量産したのに消えました。
Yeah, we mass-produced villagers but
they disappeared.
今年やったんか、活動。やってないわ。
Did we do any activities this year?
Nope, we didn't.
やってないですね。
We didn't.
やってないなー。
え、ヤバいね。アークしてる場合じゃない。
Oh, that's bad. This is no time to be
playing Ark.
すいっちゃー...こらこらこら！
Suiccha-... hey hey hey!
すみません。
Excuse me.
あたいに重なってますよ。
You're overlapping with me.
あれ、でもなんかやりませんでしたっけ今年。
なんか面接か何か。
Wait, but didn't we do something this year?
Like an interview or something.
あー、でもあれって今年じゃなかったっけ？
Ah, but wasn't that this year?
あれ、そうでしたっけ？
Oh, was it?
ま、ということでメンバー全員揃ったから...
Well, now that all members are here...
いえいえちょいちょいちょい！ 待って待って待って！
No no, wait wait wait wait!
人・人だ！
It's HR!
新しく入った白銀ノエルで... はい、インターンです。
よろしくお願いします。
I'm the newly joined Shirogane Noel...
yes, an intern, nice to meet you.
合格しましたんでね、よろしくお願いします。
I passed, so please treat me well.
ということで我ら！
And so, we are!
しらぬい・けん・せつ！ せーい！
Shiranui Construction! Hey!
ね、なんかちょっとさ、さっきと違うんだけどポーズ。
Hey, the pose is a bit different from before.
違います。リハーサルと違いますけど。
It's different. It's different from the rehearsal.
はいはい。体幹が、体幹が。
Yeah yeah. The core strength, the core strength.
いや、今日はみんな集まってくれて
ありがとうございました。
Well, thank you everyone for gathering today.
いえいえ、ありがとうございます。おめでとうございます！
No no, thank you. Congratulations!
いや、なにげにだからこれ全員がね
3Dで集まるのは初めてなんだよ。
Actually, this is the first time all of us
have gathered in 3D.
あ、そうなんだー。確かにね。嬉しいね。
Oh, is that so. True. We're happy.
ま、今日撮影をみんなにねしてもらおうかなと
思っているのでまたちょっと後で撮影会させてください。
Well, I'm thinking of having everyone take
photos today, so please let's have a
photo session later.
コションコションコション... 早い早い早い...
Shutter sounds... fast fast fast...
一曲歌おうよ！
Let's sing a song!
盛り上がる曲を用意してきたんで、みんなで一緒に
歌いたいなーなんて思うわけ。
I've prepared an exciting song, so I want to
sing it together with everyone.
なるほど。インストール中。楽曲をインストール中です。
I see. Installing. Installing the music.
しらけんらしい曲をね、ちょっと選んで。
I chose a song that's very Shiraken-like.
なるほどね。
I see.
まじか！
Really!
それは確かにそうだ。
That's certainly true.
ちょっと一回直してくるわ。ちょっと。
I'll go fix it for a second. Just a second.
あ、ちょ、ちょ、ちょ。
Wait, wait, wait...
アイス、アイス、アイスコール！
Ice, ice, ice call!
イェーイ！あ、ちょ...
Yay! Oh, wait...
あれ？今イェーイって言ったんで、それでいいんですよ。
Huh? I said "Yay" just now, so it's fine.
はい。覚えさせたのに。
Yes, even though I made them remember it.
本当だよ。
Seriously.
いや、本当にありがとうございます。
Well, thank you very much.
じゃあちょっとね、行きますか？
Now then, shall we go?
行きますか。はい。
Shall we? Yes.
えー、じゃあタイトルコール、させていただきます。
Um, then, I'll do the title call.
おねがいしまーす！
Please do!
お後がよろしっくって...よ！
May the conclusion be good!
お後がまたよろしくて
May the conclusion be good again
お先も前もよろしくね
And may the future and present be good too
ちんとん ちんとんしゃん
Chin-ton chin-ton-shan
場内万丈！
The whole venue is full of energy!
よー！
Yo!
謎ドキドキしな 仕掛けがありありです
It's mysterious and heart-pounding, full of gimmicks
女子力お悩みは 凄六 賽を振って
Girls' worries, like Sugoroku, throw the dice
ハイハイ 博も碌でもない
Hi-hi, gambling is no good
バンバン 一か八かさぁ
Bang-bang, all or nothing now
話の繋がりが 見えませんね
I can't see the connection in the story
おやおもしろく なりそうな予感
Oh my, I have a feeling it'll get interesting
目が回りそうですか
Are you getting dizzy?
いやそれでもかまわない
No, it doesn't matter
さあみんな 回って！
Come on everyone, spin!
イェーイ！
Yay!
表裏 裏返しして
Turn inside out and reverse
どんでん返しもよしよしよ
Even a plot twist is good, good
お先に行こうさぁどうぞ
Let's go ahead, come on please
お先も前もよろしくね
And may the future and present be good too
裏舞台が晴れ舞台で
Backstage becomes the main stage
無駄打ち話もよかよか
And even small talk is fine
お後がまたよろしくて
May the conclusion be good again
お先真っ白極楽だ
The future is pure white paradise
極楽だ 極楽だ
It's paradise, it's paradise
あれよと 極楽浄土！
And suddenly, pure land paradise!
ちんとん ちんとんしゃん
Chin-ton chin-ton-shan
場内騒然！
The venue is in a stir!
よー！
Yo!
手ぬぐいフキフキ見舞 扇子でパタパタします
Wiping with a towel, flapping with a folding fan
女子活 驚きの タコ上げ いとくって
Girls' activities, surprising kite flying is great
キチダラ 十を知る鳥
Kichidara, the bird that knows ten
南無阿弥陀仏 又知ら
Namu Amida Butsu, or maybe not
当たりの脈絡は ありませんね
There's no coherence in hitting the mark
あら素晴らしく 惚けそうな予兆
Oh, how wonderful, a sign I might space out
お袖が揺るむ次第
As my sleeves loosen
でもそれなら 楽しくて
But if that's the case, it's fun
さあみんな 笑って！
Come on everyone, laugh!
イェーイ！
Yay!
東の西遊び記せ
Record the play of East and West
いにしえ今もよしよしよ
Ancient and modern times are good, good
誰だお前さぁ誰だ
Who are you? Come on, who are you?
宛名は縦によろしくね
Please write the address vertically
一から百東に落ち
One to a hundred falls to the east
無慈悲娯楽もよかよか
Even ruthless entertainment is fine
お後がまたよろしくて
May the conclusion be good again
お茶の熱さに惚れちゃった
I fell in love with the heat of the tea
おやおもしろく なりそうな予感
Oh my, I have a feeling it'll get interesting
目が回りそうでした
I felt like I was getting dizzy
いやそれでもかまわない
But I don't care
さあみんな 回って！
Come on everyone, spin!
イェーイ！
Yay!
表裏 裏返しして
Turn inside out and reverse
どんでん返しもよしよしよ
Even a plot twist is good, good
お先に行こうさぁどうぞ
Let's go ahead, come on please
お先も前もよろしくね
And may the future and present be good too
裏舞台が晴れ舞台で
Backstage becomes the main stage
無駄打ち話もよかよか
And even small talk is fine
お後がまたよろしくて
May the conclusion be good again
お先真っ白極楽だ
The future is pure white paradise
極楽だ 極楽だ
It's paradise, it's paradise
極楽だ あれよと
It's paradise, and suddenly
極楽浄土！
Pure land paradise!
あれよと 極楽浄土！
And suddenly, pure land paradise!
ちんとん ちんとんしゃん
Chin-ton chin-ton-shan
場内爆笑！
The venue is in laughter!
よー！
Yo!
はい、ということで。はい皆様、立って立って立って。
Yes, and so. Everyone, stand up, stand up, stand up.
はい。
Yes.
いやぁ、皆様ね、去年の分の謝罪。放火の件とか。
Well, everyone, the apologies for last year.
Like the arson matter and so on.
ま、色々ね。去年残してきた謝罪を今ここで、
3Dで皆様にさせていただきましたので。
Well, various things. We have now made all the
apologies we left over from last year in 3D.
申し訳ございませんでした！
We are very sorry!
はい、今年からはフリーダムにやっていきたいと思いますので。
Yes, from this year onwards,
we'd like to do things with freedom.
フリーダムなんですね。
Freedom, I see.
もちろん。私も燃やすんで。新人入ったんで。
Of course. I'll burn things too.
Since a newcomer has joined.
やったー！燃やせ燃やせー！
Yay! Burn it, burn it!
はい！ということで、
Alright! So,
次の曲に行きたいんですけど、
I'd like to move on to the next song.
次の曲はね、そういう意味も含めて、ま、フリーダムにやっていきたいということで、
For the next song, I want us to perform it with a sense of freedom,
ま、ここにね、カメラを設置いたしましたんで、
so I've set up a camera here.
ここでね、あの、歌いたい人、自分の...
Here, for those who want to sing, their own...
はい、っていう感じで、あの、自分のパートとか、
Yes, like that. During your parts,
あの、今出たい！って思った時は、
or when you feel like coming out,
あの、自分から前に出てください。
please come forward on your own.
で、あの、このカメラがちょっと楽しくなったり気持ちよくなってきたりしたら、
And if this camera gets into the mood and starts having fun,
動いてくれるかもしれません。
it might even start moving.
あ、そうそう、こんな感じでね。
Oh, exactly, like this.
おーおーおー、動いてくれることも、あるかもしれませんのでね。
Whoa, it might just start moving around like this.
皆さん、あの、全力でやってくださいね！
Everyone, please give it your all!
ということでね、じゃあちょっと、次の曲最後になりますが...
Alright then, the next song will be our last...
さ、もう一曲ね、行きたいと思います！
So, I'd like to do one more song!
じゃあみんな、ちょっと、チェケラ行きますか！
Alright everyone, shall we get checking it out?
さ、最初に声を上げるのは誰だーい！？
Now, who's going to be the first to raise their voice!?
叫びてぇー！
I wanna shout it out!
はい、いらっしゃいませー！
Yes, welcome to the show!
叫びてぇ奴は集まれ 皆で爆笑
If you wanna shout, gather 'round! Everyone, laugh it up!
爆笑！
Laugh it up!
Everybody say ho!
Ho! Hip hop step jump!
叫びてぇ奴は集まれ 皆で爆笑
If you wanna shout, gather 'round! Everyone, laugh it up!
爆笑！
Laugh it up!
Everybody say ho!
Ho! Hip hop step jump!
はいはい、皆さん合言葉 みんなで手を挙げ万歳！
Alright, here's our password! Everyone, raise your hands and 'Banzai'!
万歳！
Banzai!
音に乗って楽しみたい奴 Keep on jammin'!
If you wanna ride the beat and have fun, keep on jammin'!
Yes! Keep on keep on jammin'!
怒ったり笑ったり 泣いたりして
Getting angry, laughing, or crying,
笑ったり！
Laughing!
長い旅 過ぎてく Days
our long journey goes on through the days.
Take off!
乗り遅れちゃ遅刻だよ
If you miss the start, you're late!
テンションゲージ上げる
Raise that tension gauge!
仲間たちと盛り上げる Party 羽目外し Crazy everybody!
Liven up the party with friends! Cut loose, crazy everybody!
Jump I'm ready yeah!
Hip hop step jumping!
いやー、ありがとうございましたー！
Wow, thank you so much!
いぇーい！楽しかったー！チェケラー！チェケラー！
Yay! That was fun! Chekera! Chekera!
お忙しいところね、
In the midst of your busy schedules,
お集まりいただきありがとうございました！
thank you so much for gathering here!
いえいえ、こちらこそ！
Not at all, the pleasure is ours!
もうね、でも君たちともうね...
But really, with you guys...
歌はやってられん！
I can't keep singing!
なんでー！？なんでー！？
Why!? Why!?
お前が言うなよ！ｗ
You're the one to talk! lol
疲れたからね、もう！
Because I'm exhausted!
お疲れ様です。ちょっとね、不知火建設で歌はこれで一旦終わり。に。しまして...
Good job everyone. For now, we'll wrap up the Shiranui Construction singing section...
えー！
Ehhh!
なので、
So,
あの、いつものライブ形式をとったんですけど、
well, I took the usual live concert format,
お披露目なので、
but since it's an unveiling,
ちょっと、せっかくならみんなにね、ちょっとカメラをやっていただこうかな、と思っております。
I thought I'd have everyone take on the role of photographers, if you're up for it.
なるほど。
I see.
了解でございます。
Roger that.
俺がカメラになるぜ！
I'll be the camera!
了解です！
Roger!
お前がカメラになるのか！
You're going to be the camera!?
イエーイ！
Yay!
ちなみに、お写真お得意な方はどなたですか？
By the way, who here is good at taking photos?
そうだ、ピンボケしちゃうな。
That's right, they might end up blurry.
はい！はい！みこち！みこち！みこちに任せろ！部長が！
Me! Me! Mikochi! Mikochi! Leave it to Mikochi! The President!
お、じゃあ部長、ありがてえ、任せた部長！
Oh, then President, thanks, I'm counting on you, President!
任せて！
Leave it to me!
ではでは。どんなところにこだわるのかな、部長は。
Well then. I wonder what the President will focus on.
社長、なんかポーズとか取ってくれるんですか、社長。
CEO, are you going to strike some poses, CEO?
え、何？どんなの？
Eh, what? What kind?
寝ればいい？
Should I lie down?
寝てくれるの？
You're going to lie down?
寝ればいいの？
Is lying down okay?
寝るの！？
You're lying down!?
あの、跪いてもらって、
Um, could you kneel down,
いいよ。ちょっと、社長！社長！隠して！隠して！誰か！
Okay. Wait, CEO! CEO! Hide her! Hide her! Someone!
違うの、だめだよ！見て、見て。
No, it's not like that! Look, look.
そうそう、今日、黒塗りで。
Right, right, it's blacked out today.
いいな、そういう、ちょっと寛いでる感じで。
Nice, that kind of, like you're relaxing.
あ、いい！え、ちょっとエモい、カメラ近づこうかな。
Ah, nice! Wow, that's pretty emotional, let's get the camera closer.
よいしょ。うん。いいじゃん。あ、ちょっと目開くんか。
Here we go. Yeah. That's good. Oh, you're opening your eyes a bit.
いい、あ、めっちゃ可愛い、めっちゃ可愛いな、その顔可愛い。
Nice, ah, super cute, that's so cute, that expression is cute.
あ、めっちゃ、めっちゃいいよ、すごい、めっちゃ可愛い。
Ah, really, that's really good, amazing, super cute.
あらあら、あらあら。
Oh my, oh my.
浜辺のマーメイドだ、マーメイド、美しい。
She's a mermaid on the beach, a mermaid, beautiful.
このステージで何をやってるんだろう。
I wonder what she's doing on this stage.
なかなかいいじゃないですか。
Isn't this quite good?
いや、こういう悩ましいお披露目はやっぱさ、
I mean, this kind of seductive unveiling is, you know,
本当に。社長、あれかな、ちょっと雌みが...
Really. CEO, is it just me, or is there a bit of a feminine...
雌みって言うな！
Don't say "feminine"!
ね、可愛い。
Right, she's cute.
みこも、社長と一緒に撮りたいな。
I want to take a photo with the CEO too.
あ、いいよ。撮る？じゃあ、すいちゃんにカメラ代わるよ。
Ah, sure. Want to? Then, I'll switch the camera to Suichan.
お、優しい！みこめ！
Oh, how kind! Mikome!
よいしょっと、よろしく。ちゃんと持ってもらってね。
Here we go, please take care of it. Make sure you hold it properly.
あ、あら！イエーイ！いいよ、社長、可愛い！
Ah, oh! Yay! Looking good, CEO, cute!
美しい。あれ、みこち、なんか小さくない？
Beautiful. Wait, Mikochi, aren't you a bit small?
ちょっと社長、もう、ハグ、ハグとか、おねおねで。
Wait, CEO, come on, a hug, give us a hug, please.
あら、顔隠さないで。
Oh, don't hide your face.
ハグ、ハグ！
Hug, hug!
あ、ここら辺可愛い、幸せそうだ。
Ah, this part is cute, you look happy.
いいよ、もっと近づいて。はい、可愛い！
Nice, get closer. Yes, cute!
はい、ポーズ！
Okay, pose!
可愛いね。
Cute, isn't it?
いいね、じゃあ、ちょっとすいちゃんも。
Nice, then, how about Suichan too.
お、ポーズをさせていただきます。まずは下からカメラで攻めます。
Oh, I'll strike a pose. First, I'll attack with the camera from below.
いいね、足が。足がやべえ。
Nice, the legs. The legs are incredible.
全身可愛い。いいよ、じゃあ、後ろとかも見せてください。
Full body cute. Nice, then, please show us your back too.
あら、可愛い。そこから社長、可愛い！
Oh, cute. From there, CEO, cute!
背中美人、最強なんだが。綺麗。髪の毛も綺麗。
A beauty from the back, she's the strongest. Beautiful. Her hair is beautiful too.
え、ちょっとさ、くるんって一回転してくださいよ。
Hey, could you, like, do a quick spin?
くるんって一回転？そう。
A quick spin? Yeah.
わあ！可愛い！
Wow! Cute!
エロみがすごいよ。
The sexiness is amazing.
髪の毛がめっちゃサラサラなんだわ。
Her hair is really silky smooth.
シャンプーのCMみたいだ。セクシーでしょ。
It's like a shampoo commercial. Sexy, isn't it?
セクシー。社長の脇、脇。
Sexy. CEO's armpits, armpits.
みんな大好き脇、はい！
Everyone's favorite armpits, here we go!
いい、めっちゃいい！あ、なんか映り込もうとしてる奴がいる。
Nice, really nice! Ah, looks like someone's trying to photobomb.
映り込むつもりはない、輝かせた脇を撮りたいだけなんだ。
I'm not trying to photobomb, I just want to take a photo of those shining armpits.
脇に夢中だったわ。
I was totally focused on the armpits.
はい、じゃあ、ちょっと私もふーたんと撮ろうかな。
Okay, then, I'll take a photo with Fuutan too.
あら、待ってよ。
Oh, wait a minute.
私が撮るよ、代わるよ。
I'll take it, I'll switch.
お前はええて！わちゃわちゃ、社長と撮りたいの。
You're fine! *Commotion*, I want to take a photo with the CEO.
そうだ、ポルカが撮る。かっこいい感じ、かっこいい感じ。
Right, Polka will take it. Something cool, something cool.
背中合わせで。自撮りしようかな。
Back to back. Should we take a selfie?
あら、かっこいい、撮ってるふりをして。
Oh, cool, pretend like you're taking one.
あ、めっちゃいいじゃん！可愛いな！
Ah, that's really good! So cute!
これ、君らお揃いみたいだね、凄いわ。
This, it looks like you two are matching, it's amazing.
等身がやばい。
The proportions are crazy.
あ、いい、自撮りできた！
Ah, nice, I got the selfie!
可愛い、いい、二人とも。
Cute, nice, both of you.
あ、そうそう、そういうの、そういうの。
Ah, right, right, like that, like that.
いい、素晴らしい、素晴らしい。
Nice, wonderful, wonderful.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
じゃ、ポルカも撮る、ポルカも撮る。
Then, I'll take one of Polka too, I'll take one of Polka too.
私が撮る、私が撮る。
I'll take it, I'll take it.
ポルカプロデュースだよね、プロデュース。
It's a Polka production, isn't it? Production.
プロデュースさせて。
Let me produce it.
すいちゃんプロデュースしない、今は。
I'm not producing Suichan right now.
フレアをプロデュースする。いろんな顔して。
I'm producing Flare. Make different expressions.
あのさ、ちょっとさ、ハートとかさ、きゅってできたりする？
You know, could you, like, make a heart shape, tightly?
こういうこと？あ、それ！
Like this? Ah, that's it!
社長、そんな顔していいんですか！
CEO, is it okay to make an expression like that!?
いい、完璧！おててを顎とかに乗せて。
Nice, perfect! Put your hands under your chin.
なんでそのボーズなんだよ。
Why that pose?
顎とかに乗せてさ、ちょっとさ、上目遣いで...
Put them under your chin, and then, with an upturned gaze...
上目遣い的な...
Looking up like this...
下から見てる... そうそうそうそうそう！
Looking from below... Yes, yes, yes, yes!
そして目をつぶって。はい、おてて...
And close your eyes. Okay, hands...
...おめめをパチ。
...eyes open.
おめめをパチ。おめめをパチ。
Eyes open. Eyes open.
おめめを... ハート浮かべて。
Eyes... float some hearts.
ハート... シュー！
Heart... whoosh!
パチ！ おお！ 近づく近づく！
Snap! Ooh! Getting closer, closer!
近づく近づく近づく近づく！
Closer, closer, closer, closer!
近づくそこです！ 近づいて... ああ！
Closer, right there! Getting close... ah!
上目遣い！ ああ、かわいい！
Looking up! Ah, so cute!
かわいい！ なんだこれ！ 顔かわいい！
Cute! What is this! Her face is so cute!
ありがとう！ スクショ撮る？ 楽しんじゃった。
Thank you! Taking screenshots? I had too much fun.
行っちゃう？ ありがとう。他には...
Moving on? Thank you. What else...
...どんな顔できんの？ ふーたん。顔芸を...
...can you do with your face, Fuutan? Funny faces...
ワシャワシャワシャワシャ... ワシャワシャワシャ...
Washa washa washa...
後ろから振り向いてからさ...
How about turning around from the back...
...おめめキラってして。おお！ それそれ！
...and making your eyes sparkle. Ooh! That's it!
後ろから... なんか背中見せて、背中。
From the back... show your back, your back.
背中？ 背中見せて...
My back? Show your back...
...顔だけこっちに。はい、フレアちゃんこっち向いて。
...and just your face this way. Flare-chan, look here.
キラ！
Sparkle!
ああかわいい！ かわいい！ よいよいよい！
Ah, cute! Cute! Good, good, good!
かわいいじゃん！ 恥ずかしいな... 持ち上げられた。
Isn't she cute! It's embarrassing... being hyped up.
はい持ち上げます！ よいしょよいしょよいしょよいしょ！
Hyping you up! Heave-ho, heave-ho...!
よいしょよいしょ！ お写真撮らなくていいの？ 一緒に。
Heave-ho! Don't you want to take photos? Together.
撮りたい撮りたい！ 団長が... カメラを。入ります。
I want to! Danchou will... take the camera. I'm in.
ありがとうございます！ よいしょ！ いえーい！
Thank you very much! Heave-ho! Yay!
あれ？ あれ？ 社長... 社長が映ってない。
Huh? Huh? The CEO... the CEO isn't in the shot.
いえーい！ ポルカはどういうふうに映ったいの？
Yay! How should Polka be in the shot?
うん。あの、社長、一緒にハートを作りましょう。
Yeah. Um, CEO, let's make a heart together.
なるほどね、そういうふうね。限界オタクだ。
I see, like that. Total obsessed fan.
はいチーズ！ めちゃくちゃ撮るんや。新たな横好きで...
Say cheese! Taking so many photos. In a new pose...
...よいしょ！ はいチーズ！ はいチーズ！
...heave-ho! Say cheese! Say cheese!
なんでこうなっちまうんだ... もしかして...
Why does it end up like this... maybe...
ハート！ ダイナミック！ 脇がいい！ 脇がいい！
Heart! Dynamic! Armpits are good!
なんだろうそれは... セクシーだから。いいね！
What is that... because it's sexy. Nice!
ねー！ なんだかハート作ろうか。新社長だ！
Right! Let's make a heart somehow. It's the new CEO!
楽しみ... お、情けのハートだ。お、身長足りない。
Exciting... Oh, a heart of mercy. Not enough height.
身長足りない... よいしょ！ 足りない... 足りない！
Not enough height... heave-ho! Not enough!
いいえ！ ボレボレハート！ ありがとう！
No! Smitten heart! Thank you!
はいありがとうございます。やっとね、どうもありがとう。
Okay, thank you very much. Finally, thank you.
ちょいちょいちょい！ 待ってくれ！ 団長も撮りたい！
Wait, wait, wait! Danchou also wants to take one!
でも今撮ってくれてるじゃん。一緒に撮りたいんだよ！
But you're taking them now. I want one together!
ノエルプロデュースでなんか。ああそうか。いいじゃん。
Produced by Noel. Ah, right. Good idea.
いいですか？ まだ終わりませんよ。ああ大丈夫です。
Is it okay? We're not done yet. Ah, it's fine.
じゃ、なに？ めちゃ考えてたのがあるんだ。
Then, what? There's something I've been thinking about.
なに？ だっちゅーのしてください。ネタに走るなよ！
What? Please do 'Dacchu-no'. Don't go for the gag!
よーやめよ！ だってみんな結構表情とかしたから。
Hey, stop it! But everyone else did expressions.
後で反省会だな。やばい、クビになっちまう。
Reflection meeting later. I'll get fired.
だっちゅーの... ああ！ ああ！ ああ！
Dacchu-no... Ah! Ah! Ah!
隙間から見える谷間がやばい。ちょっとしゃがんでよ。
The cleavage in the gap is insane. Squat down a bit.
それ上から撮りて。しゃがんで。ノエル身長高いから...
Take it from above. Squat. Since Noel is tall...
こっち見てだっちゅーのして！ ああかわいい！
Look here and do 'Dacchu-no'! Ah, cute!
おいおいおい！ 俺の隣にフレアがいる！ きゃー！
Oi oi oi! Flare is right next to me! Kyaa!
つまみ... あれ？ フレアちゃん！ みっこ！ みこち！
Snack... Huh? Flare-chan! Miko! Mikochi!
ちょっと待ってくれ！ ノエルも！ いえーい！
Wait a minute! Noel too! Yay!
いいね！ 新人ちゃんが遠いよ。いいえ！ いえーい！
Nice! The newcomer is far away. No! Yay!
ちょっと待ってください。新人のこと忘れている。
Please wait. You're forgetting about the newcomer.
新人扱いはこんなもんや。わかった！ カメラマン入るよ。
That's how it is for newcomers. Okay! Cameraman's in.
やった！ フレアと一緒だ！ よいしょ！ 最高！
Yay! I'm with Flare! Heave-ho! The best!
ノエフレがカメラしてくれてるけど...
NoeFure are doing the camera, but...
また忘れたよ！ カメラマンさんが撮ってくれるよ。
Forgot again! The cameraman will take it.
隣に行ってね。みんなで... いえーい！ いえーい！
Go stand next to her. Everyone... Yay! Yay!
いえーい！ チーズ！ きれい！ きれい！
Yay! Cheese! Beautiful! Beautiful!
素敵！ いえーい！ チーズ！ これちょっと... 角にしちゃお。
Wonderful! Yay! Cheese! Let's make these horns.
カメラ... 後でサインとか書いてさ、お免状あげたい。
Camera... sign it later and upload the photo.
チェキみたいなやつ。チェキしよう。ハート作れる？
Like a cheki photo. Let's do cheki. Can you do a heart?
ニコちハート作れる？ 指ハート。おお指ハート。
Can Nikochi do a heart? Finger heart. Oh, finger heart.
お前らが一番怪しいハート。難しいのよこれ...
You guys have the most suspicious heart. This is hard...
...だんだんこれなんか... 桃。きゃぴきゃぴ。これは何だ。
...this is starting to look like... a peach. What is this.
なにか、ハートのようななにか。
Something, like a heart or something.
ハート？
A heart?
まるやん。
It's a circle.
おさるさんポーズでいいよ、おさるさんポーズ。
The monkey pose is fine, monkey pose.
いいねいいね。
Nice, nice.
すべてを諦めれたね。
You've given up on everything.
かわいいな、オッケーン。
Cute, okay.
いいね。
Nice.
ノエルはそれでいいの？
Is Noel okay with that?
ちょっと触りたくなっちゃった。
I kind of wanted to touch it.
やっぱしらけんなんだよな。
As expected of Shiraken.
しらけんしか勝たん！
Shiraken is the best!
えっとさ、あれだけやらせてほしいんですけど。
Um, I just want to do that one thing.
なに？
What?
チャリで来た。
I came by bike.
ああ、チャリ、あ、やる？やりたいやりたい。
Oh, bike, oh, you wanna do it? Let's do it.
チャリで来た。
I came by bike.
写真撮ろうぜ！
Let's take a photo!
あれか。
That one?
しらけんぽいな。こうだな。
That's so Shiraken-like. Like this.
八日燃やしたんだ。
I burned the eighth day.
この後このステージ燃やすぜ。
I'll burn this stage after this.
やめて！
Stop it!
やめてよ、ねねの、やめてよ。
Stop it, Nene's... stop it.
炎上！
Controversy!
なんで謝罪しなきゃいけないの？
Why do we have to apologize?
炎上、炎上じゃい！
Controversy, it's a controversy!
これからもよろしく！
Please support us from now on too!
よろしくー！
Please support us!
これからもしらけんをよろしく！
Please support Shiraken from now on too!
よろしくー！よろしくー！
Please support us!
よろしくー！
次は謝罪会見だな。
Next is the apology press conference.
そうですね。
True.
先に今から謝罪しておく？
Should we apologize in advance now?
じゃ、確かに。
Yeah, actually.
今後のことを考えてちょっとみんなで謝罪して終わろうか。
Thinking about the future, let's all apologize and end this.
わかりました。
Understood.
え、うそじゃん。
Wait, you're joking.
お披露目なのに！伏線だったんだ。
Even though it's an unveiling! It was foreshadowing.
皆さん、今後もですね、我々たぶんやらかすと思うんですけども、
Everyone, we'll probably mess up in the future too,
しらけんはこれからも楽しく、自由にやっていくので、よろしくおねがいします！
but Shiraken will continue to have fun and be free, so please support us!
よろしくお願いします！
Please support us!
今回の件については誠に申し訳ございませんでした！
We are truly sorry about this matter!
何も謝ることないんだけども。
There's nothing to apologize for, though.
申し訳ございませんでした！
We are sorry!
お披露目最高でした！
The unveiling was the best!
はい、ということで。
Yes, so...
いや〜嵐が過ぎ去りましたね。
Man, that was a storm.
今日は噛まないぞって思いながら何度か何度ことか。
I thought I wouldn't stutter today, but how many times has it been...
ついにですね、最後になってしまいましたけれども。
Finally, it's the end.
あのですね、何もないのもなんだなと思って、
I thought it'd be bad to have nothing,
ちょっとね、運営さんとご相談してちょっとご用意させていただいたものがあるんですよね。
so I consulted with management and prepared something.
ちょっと見てもらってもいいですか？
Can you take a look at this?
こちら！
This!
デレレレレ。2月20日、ま、この後ですね、この後発売します。
Drumroll. Feb 20th, well, after this, it'll be on sale.
不知火フレア3D新ビジュアルお披露目記念ということで、
To commemorate the Shiranui Flare 3D New Visual Unveiling,
3D新ビジュアルアクリルスタンド、こちら販売させていただきます。
we will be selling the 3D New Visual Acrylic Stand.
ぜひぜひこちらもお手にとっていただけたらなと思っております。
I hope you'll pick it up.
みんなに可愛い私をもっともっといっぱい見てもらって、
I want everyone to see more of my cute self,
なんなら飾ってもらえたら嬉しいなって思ってます。
and even display it if possible.
さてさて、これ以外にもちょっと告知をもう一つさせていただきたくてですね。
Well then, I'd like to make one more announcement.
実は、オリ曲ではないんですけど、この後ね、カバーを一曲上げさせていただきたいなと。
Actually, it's not an original song, but I'd like to release a cover song after this.
思っております。曲はこちら。
I'm thinking. The song is this.
「三原色」、こちら上げさせていただきます。YOASOBIさんの「三原色」です。
"Three Primary Colors", I'll be releasing this. It's YOASOBI's "Three Primary Colors".
イラスト、佐久道先生に描いていただけました。
Illustrations were done by Sakumichi-sensei.
こちら動画も、むつ子くん、すごいことになっておりますので、ぜひぜひ楽しみにしていてください。
The video by Mutsu-kun is also amazing, so please look forward to it.
ではですね、もう最後の曲になってしまうわけなんですけれども。
Now then, it's finally time for the last song.
寂しいな...寂しいなって思いながらも、やっぱり楽しいものには終わりもつきものなわけなんですよね。
It's lonely... While thinking it's lonely, fun things must come to an end.
まあでも最後はエモい感じで終わりたいなって思います。
But I want to end it with an emotional feeling.
私が、なんだろう、ちょっと辛い時に聴いてめっちゃ救われた曲というか、
It's a song that helped me through hard times,
めちゃめちゃ泣いたりとかもしたような曲なので、
and a song I cried a lot to,
歌詞すっごくエモくて素晴らしい曲なのでね、みんなにもちょっと聴いてもらいたいし、歌いたいなと思ったので。
the lyrics are very emotional and it's a wonderful song, so I wanted everyone to hear it and I wanted to sing it.
それでは聴いてください。セレナーデ。
So, please listen. Serenade.
セレナーデ
作詞 / 作曲 : 岡崎 律子
Serenade
Lyrics / Composition : Ritsuko Okazaki
初めての宝物よ
My first treasure
こんなにも好き
I love it this much
…君になって
...becoming you,
強くて弱い心
a heart that is strong yet weak.
時には寂しがるけど
Though it sometimes feels lonely,
君が笑うと
whenever you smile,
それだけでも嬉しくて
that alone makes me so happy
全てが報われるんだ
that it makes everything feel worthwhile.
俯いてた日は
On the days I was looking down,
ここから見てたのはぬかるみ
all I saw from here was the mud,
でも今は空を見上げてる
but now I'm looking up at the sky.
途方に暮れる背中に
To your back that seems so lost,
言葉を掛けたいけど
I want to reach out with words, but...
土砂降りに濡れた肩を
Your shoulders drenched in the downpour—
すぐにも抱きたいけれど
I want to hold you right away, but...
いつもいつでも求めていてくれなくていい
You don't have to need me all the time.
どんな日も君を知ってる
I know the real you, no matter the day.
心の鍵を開けるのは 強い力じゃなく
What unlocks the heart isn't brute force,
真っ直ぐに想う気持ち
but feelings that are straightforward and true.
君が笑うと
Whenever you smile,
それだけでも嬉しくて
that alone makes me so happy
全てが報われるんだ
that it makes everything feel worthwhile.
俯いてた日は
On the days I was looking down,
ここから見てたのはぬかるみ
all I saw from here was the mud,
でも今は空を見上げてる
but now I'm looking up at the sky.
今日も頑張ろう
Let's do our best today too.
負けない強さを持とう
Let's have the strength to never give up,
愛する人のためにも
for the sake of the ones we love.
不知火フレア 新3Dお披露目 お待たせ
Shiranui Flare New 3D Reveal: Thanks for waiting!
不知火フレア 3D新ビジュアル お披露目
Shiranui Flare 3D New Visual Reveal